Sodeinde Oluwaloni Richard

Front-End Engineer

Alagomeji, Yaba Lagos, Nigeria. +(234) 7064879221 lonnyrichard77@gmail.com

Professional Brief

Front - End Engineer with 3+ years experience in developing production-grade, user-friendly, interactive, and performant applications that convert business requirements into code.

I'm also passionate and excited about the thought of learning new and emerging technologies, teaching them to my peers and rising talents in the technology ecosystem thereby making a positive transition in the tech space and in any organization I find myself in.

Skills and Technologies used

HTML & CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS, REACT NATIVE, GRAPHQL, TYPESCRIPT, FIREBASE

Experience

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Bundakten Digital Solution – *Front-End/Mobile Engineer*

- Developed a landing page for the company https://www.bundakten.com/
- Working on an admin dashboard for a logistics mobile application mainly used for monitoring performance, sales, transactions, and also for analytics.
- Developing a saas mobile application that involves logistics and product delivery. (currently in development)

AUGUST 2020 - NOVEMBER 2021(CONTRACT)

AreaExpress – *Front-End Lead/Engineer*

- Managed a team of 4 that worked on nine(9) web applications which includes four(4) user-facing applications and five(5) administrative dashboards.
- In the course of development, we developed a restaurant application an eCommerce application a logistics application, and one central application that houses all the three other applications, from this main app you can register and access all other applications.
- We also developed an administrative view for all the applications which has the following functionalities: monitoring performance and transactions of each app, CRUD Operations,
- We developed a super administrator module that has the functionality of creating administrators, managing them, and assigning admin credentials to them whenever they want to gain access.

FEBRUARY 2020 - JUNE 2021

Asseco Software Nigeria - Front-End Engineer/Software Support

- Developing a sales automation platform that allows merchants/ store owners to create and
 design their e-commerce store, also allows them to view the overall performance of the
 store in terms of sales, customer engagements, and profit margin.
- Supported a two-factor authentication application by engaging issues that clients experience in their interacting with the application.
- Was involved in the development of a tax automation system that gave the client the
 satisfaction of monitoring taxpayers, analytics in form of data visualization also enables tax
 administrators to set instructions about tax remittance for banks involved in the collection
 of these taxes.

JUNE 2019 - JANUARY 2020

ScholarX Technologies - Front-End Engineer

- Developed a scholarship management application that manages scholarships for out-of-school kids which enabled them to access funds provided by partners and external donors
- Developed a website for an upcoming fundraiser event for the company, this website allows you to see the details of the event and contact the company for the inquiry of ticket sales.
- Involved in the design thinking and architectural design of a learning platform that helps unemployed graduates learn a tech skill after which they'd be referred to the company's partners to intern and get hands-on practice after all these had been completed there's a Pay-As-You-Earn system that produces a lenient repayment schedule for the recently employed.

Education

2016

Bowen University, Osun State Nigeria - BSc Accounting

Profile

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/sodeinde-oluwaloni-richard/

Github - https://github.com/lonnyrichard27

Projects worked on

www.areaexpress.co

https://oluwalonirichard.netlify.app/

https://www.bundakten.com/

https://crypto-info-app.netlify.app/

https://12-dictionary.netlify.app/